( regal fanfare music )
( heavy ominous music )
( engine rumbling )
Hello , Nicholas .
Hello , Rex , how are you ?
Fine , fine .
Where is Simon ?
Well , when did you last see him ?
Three months ago .
Three months ?
Well , do you think he 's in trouble ?
Wouldn 't he have told me if he was ?
Well , perhaps he told Richard or Marie .
No , they haven 't seen him since Christmas .
Then something must be wrong .
Let 's go to his club .
He isn 't there anymore , Rex .
He bought a house , a large one .
What on Earth for ?
Exactly .
Well , do you know where it is ?
Mr. Simon Aron 's house .
( ominous music )
( doorbell ringing )
Mr. Aron ?
( people chattering )
Good Lord .
Nicholas .
Simon .
Rex .
Hello , Simon .
What a wonderful surprise .
We must apologize for breaking in on your party
like this , Simon .
Oh , it isn 't a party .
It 's just a meeting of a little
astronomical society I 've joined .
Really ?
Well , let me introduce you to the members .
Countess , may I introduce my friends ?
The Duc de Richleau .
Madame .
Enchantee .
[ Simon ] And Rex Van Ryn .
Countess d 'Urfe .
Madame .
Monsieur .
Tanith , Mr. Mocata ,
I 'd like to introduce you to my friends .
The Duc de Richleau , Mr. Van Ryn .
Ms. Carlisle , Mr. Mocata .
[ Mocata ] It 's always a pleasure to meet Simon 's friends .
Mademoiselle .
Monsieur .
Mr. Van Ryn .
I believe we have met before .
Have we ?
I don 't remember .
So you 've joined an astronomical society , have you , Simon ?
We were pleased to welcome him to our circle .
Yes .
That explains why I haven 't seen anything of you
for these last few months
and why you appear to have forgotten our reunion tonight .
Well , I was - -
Would you excuse me for a moment , gentlemen ?
There 's something I must say to Simon .
You 're friends of Simon 's ?
Yes , indeed , mademoiselle .
His father , Rex , and I were companions
in the Escadrille Lafayette .
And when he died you vowed to keep an eye on Simon ?
Yes .
Well , when did you join this group ?
We were never told that ...
I don 't understand .
Surely we 're not meant to be more than 13 .
Oh , we 're not members .
[ Tanith ] What ?
We only stopped by to see Simon .
I 've just come back from the continent .
You see , we have this - -
Excuse me .
( people chattering )
What 's going on now ?
We 're going to be asked to leave , Rex .
You move among the guests
and listen to what they have to say .
Rex , old friend .
I hate to say it , but I 'm gonna have to throw you out .
The meeting 's due to start very shortly .
It 's better than new , but we must learn to control it .
[ Woman ] Control ?
Yes , yes , I see exactly what you mean .
An organization ...
Do you think we shall have a good meeting tonight ?
If the weather improves , we shall learn much .
It is his natal conjunction
which should help immeasurably .
Two years ago in Berlin ,
I experienced exactly similar conditions .
That is most interesting .
[ Man ] It is all a question of strong ties .
Mars , in conjunction with Saturn , of course .
Yes , sir , but you mustn 't call him Abraham
until deep pull is executed .
Now why is that ?
Well , there 's got to be an initiation ceremony first ,
then we can call him .
Oh .
This looks like a splendid wine , Simon .
And you always had excellent taste .
Nicholas , I feel dreadfully embarrassed .
I 'd love to have you stay but , well ,
it 's not an ordinary meeting , you see .
And , well , you and Rex not being members .
Oh , don 't you worry about that , my dear chap .
It 's perfectly all right .
We both understand perfectly , don 't we , Rex ?
Of course .
I feel terrible about missing our reunion tonight .
It 's a special meeting .
We must get together very soon , perhaps tomorrow ?
Oh , Simon , I see you 've got an observatory here .
I 'm very interested in astronomy , and I 'd like to have
a look through your telescope , if I may .
I 'll only be five minutes .
What do you want to look at his blasted telescope for ?
I don 't .
Simon , those charts .
They 're not astronomical , are they ?
No , good Lord , no .
They 're just for decoration .
Relics , Middle Ages nonsense , you know .
It 's clever of you to extend the decorative scheme
to the floor .
Yes .
( rattling )
Well , if you 'd like to see the - -
Sounds like mice .
( dramatic music )
You 'll have to go now .
[ Rex ] What in the name of ?
You fool !
I 'd rather see you dead than meddling with black magic .
Let go of me .
I didn 't ask you to come here tonight .
Even my oldest friends have no right to butt in
on my private affairs .
Will someone please say - -
I 'm sorry , Simon , but I feel like a father
who sees his child trying to pick live coals out of a fire .
Will someone kindly tell me what 's going on ?
Chickens in a basket , diagrams on a floor .
Do these mean something to you ?
It means that Simon here is playing
the most dangerous game known to mankind .
Oh , come on , Nicholas .
Rex is right , you 're making too much of it .
Then you have no objection if we stay ?
You aren 't members of the circle .
Circle ?
[ Simon ] The society .
If we stay , there 'd be more than 13 , wouldn 't there ?
Look , Simon , I think you will admit
that whilst Rex and I have been your closest friends
for more than 10 years now , we have never at any time
stressed our age or our greater experience .
Now tonight I 'm gonna break that rule .
I 'm considerably older than you are , Simon .
And although I 've never spoken about it ,
I 've made a very deep study of these esoteric doctrines .
I beg of you as I 've never begged anything
in my life before , give up this desperately dangerous
adventure and leave this house with us immediately .
I can 't .
Then let us stay .
Impossible .
( blow thudding ) ( dramatic music )
( blow thudding ) ( vase shattering )
Put him down there , Rex .
Thank you , Max .
Can you wait outside ?
Well , I wonder what he 's gonna say .
Nothing .
I 'm only bringing him round to put him to sleep again .
Makes about as much sense as anything else has tonight .
Tilt the lampshade towards me , Rex .
Look into the mirror , Simon .
Look into the mirror .
Keep looking and listen to me .
You have been hurt and your mind is troubled ,
but you are with your friends now .
And there is nothing more to worry about .
I 'm going to send you to sleep , Simon .
Your eyes will close as soon as I touch them .
You will wake up at 10 o 'clock tomorrow morning ,
and your mind will be free from all pain
and from all anxiety .
Open your eyes , Simon .
Stand up .
I 'm going to place this symbol of protection
around your neck .
Once it is there , you will not remove it .
Now you will go directly to my bedroom where you will
lie down and you will fall into an immediate sleep .
Max , show Mr. Aron to my room .
Thank God that 's over .
I might agree with you
if I knew what you were talking about .
We can certainly make good use of these .
To our reunion , Rex .
No questions ?
Hocus-pocus , mumbo-jumbo , black magic .
Rex , do you believe in evil ?
As an idea .
[ Nicholas ] Do you believe in the power of darkness ?
As a superstition .
Now there you are wrong .
The power of darkness is more than just a superstition .
It is a living force which can be tapped
at any given moment of the night .
( dramatic music )
( Simon gagging )
I tell you these people are devil worshipers .
That 's ridiculous .
These are facts , Rex , not superstition .
The final proof was in the hamper .
They were about to practice the age-old sacrifice
to their infernal master ,
the slaughter of the black cockerel and the white hen .
( Max knocking )
Yes ?
I thought I 'd better bring this to you , Excellency .
My God .
He 's all right now , sir .
Did you remove this , Max ?
- Yes , sir . - Why ?
It was choking him to death , Excellency .
He rang for me , and when I got here his face
was almost black , his tongue protruding .
I should have known .
I 'm sorry , sir , if I 've done something wrong .
No , that 's all right , it 's not your fault .
We can only hope that he 's gone back to his house .
Shall I look upstairs while you try down here ?
I think it 's better if we stay together .
Rubbish .
Don 't worry , I 'll scream if I so much as smell anything .
All right .
( dramatic music )
Well ?
Not a sign , you ?
He 's not here .
Unless up there .
It 's possible .
Is it getting colder up here , or is it my imagination ?
No , it isn 't your imagination .
At least we 've saved your lives .
But no Simon .
No .
It might help us to locate him if we knew
the real names of those people who were here tonight .
Real names ?
Yes .
In order to become a follower
of the so-called Left Hand Path ,
one has to be re-baptized in the cause
and take the name of some past notable of the occult .
That girl , for instance , Ms. Carlisle .
I have seen her before .
You have , where ?
Biarritz , at the casino .
She was with that old woman , you know , the cigar smoker .
Simon called her Tanith , didn 't he ?
So ?
Tanith happens to be the name of the moon goddess
of the Carthaginians .
You mean she 's been re-baptized ?
Probably .
Well , let 's see what we can find and get out of here .
What is it ?
Fantastic .
The Clavicule of Solomon .
Valuable ?
Invaluable .
What 's it made of , cork ?
( ominous music )
It 's cold .
My God .
Don 't look at the eyes , Rex .
Don 't look at the eyes .
Don 't pull away .
Try to hold back .
( speaking in foreign language )
Run !
( dramatic music )
Oh , I take back everything I said .
I 've never been so scared in all my life .
I 'm sorry , Rex .
Sorry , for saving my life ?
I should never have allowed you into that place .
Forget it , we 're out .
That 's all that matters .
Wasn 't very pleasant , was it ?
Pleasant ?
What in God 's name was that thing ?
Some infernal spirit given entry
into the world by Mocata 's powers .
Obviously , Mocata is one of the great adepts .
Perhaps even an Ipsissimus .
A what ?
An Ipsissimus , a master of the highest grade .
Simon is in his hands ,
and he 's about to be baptized into the service of evil .
When does it take place ?
Baptism must take place on a true Sabbat
with at least one coven of 13 believers present .
After tonight , I can 't believe that they would dare
to hold another meeting , unless ...
( dramatic music )
What is it , Nicholas ?
Do you realize what today 's date is , Rex ?
April the 29th , why ?
Mocata isn 't going to miss the chance of giving Simon
his devil 's baptism at the grand Sabbat of the year .
What are you talking about ?
Tomorrow night , the eve of May Day .
In 24 hours , Simon could be lost to us forever .
What can we do ?
We find the girl .
Thank you , good bye .
It 's all right , Rex .
I 've found her .
Where ?
She was in a London hotel , the London Plaza .
I never knew there were so many hotels in London .
It was the 28th one I tried .
You should have woken me .
Just as well you slept .
You need to be more alert today than any other day
of your life .
Well , let 's go then .
You 'll have to go alone , Rex .
It 's vital that I should go to the British Museum
and examine certain occult volumes that are kept under
constant lock and key .
Fortunately , the curator 's a friend of mine .
[ Rex ] Well , do you want me to bring Tanith back here ?
No , I want you to keep her as far away
from London as possible .
Well , what if I take her to Richard 's house ?
Yes , perfect .
I 'll telephone to say you 're on your way down .
I 'll see you there about three .
It should give you plenty of time .
We 'll be there .
Oh , may I borrow a car ?
Yes , take any of them .
Thanks .
What is it you have to say to me ?
I haven 't much time .
There 's so many things I must do before we leave .
We ?
The Countess and I , we 're traveling together .
To the Sabbat ?
Of course .
Couldn 't you have spoken to me there ?
In front of Mr. Mocata ?
I 'm hoping that whatever you have to say to me
has nothing to do with my loyalty to him .
It doesn 't .
[ Tanith ] What is it , then ?
Well , it 's just , I just wanted to take you to lunch .
If you 're free , that is .
Take me to lunch ?
[ Rex ] Does that sound such a bad idea ?
Mr. Van Ryn , you know as well as I do
that neither of us is free to give our lives to such things .
Why not let me be the judge of that ?
I think you 'd better drive me back .
Mr. Van Ryn ?
( tires screech )
Don 't ever do that again .
What has this Mocata done to make you so afraid of him ?
It 's what he 'll do .
Oh God , it 's what he 'll do .
Where are you taking me ?
To see De Richleau .
Look , there 's nothing to be afraid of .
You know better than that .
If I 'm not at the Sabbat in time - -
Is that so important to you ?
My satanic baptism ?
You mean , you haven 't been re-baptized yet ?
But your name , Tanith .
I was named that at birth .
Then you still have a chance .
Chance ?
Look , De Richleau can help you .
Believe me , Tanith , he can .
I 've known De Richleau for many years .
And if there 's anyone you can put your trust in , it 's him .
( eerie music )
[ Mocata ] Tanith .
Look at me , Tanith , in the mirror .
Listen carefully to what I say .
You 'll have nothing to worry about once we get down
to Richard and Marie in the country .
In the country ?
Yes , where we 're going .
Haven 't you been listening ?
Yes , I 've been listening .
( Richard humming )
Peggy , run and wash your hands , will you ?
Oh , Mummy , must I ?
Oh , Peggy , yes you must .
Uncle Rex will be here in a minute .
Won 't he have to wash his hands ?
Yes , I expect so .
Why can 't I wait till Uncle Rex comes , then go and wash ?
Then I won 't be late .
Off , and take that hat off .
[ Peggy ] It 's to protect my head .
We 're having a picnic luncheon , not a gymkhana .
If I fall over and split my head wide open - -
It 'll be my fault , and I 'll be very sorry .
Now hurry yourself .
- She 'll go like a bird now . - ( horn honking )
Good .
This must be Rex and his mysterious woman .
[ Peggy ] There 's a car coming .
Probably be Uncle Rex .
- Uncle Rex ! - ( horn honking )
[ Marie ] Careful !
Uncle Rex !
Hello , Peggy , Marie , Richard .
( engine revving )
What 's going on ?
I must take your car .
Simon 's life depends on it .
He didn 't stay long , did he ?
( water splashing )
( tires screeching )
( dramatic music )
[ Mocata ] Do not be afraid .
I 'm still with you .
He will never catch you .
( dramatic music )
( tires screeching )
( glass shattering )
Listen , Tanith , listen and obey .
( tires screeching )
( metal crunching )
( people chattering )
( ominous music )
( speaking in foreign language )
( flame roaring )
( followers cheering )
( blood splashing )
( phone ringing )
Hello ?
Rex .
What ?
It 's all started .
I couldn 't phone you earlier , I would have lost them .
Where are you ?
Crossroads .
Yes , yes .
Yes , I 've got that .
Now listen , you 're not to do anything
until I get there , do you understand ?
You 're not to do anything at all .
Right .
Three turns to the left and then one to the right .
The last bit has a very rough surface .
Well done , Rex .
Here , take these .
What are they ?
The results of my morning 's research at the British Museum .
Put one in each pocket of your jacket .
And may I ask what they are ?
Salt and mercury , effective against the dark forces .
They will protect you and Simon , if we can save him .
And you ?
I have other protection .
( lively drum music ) ( followers shouting )
There .
We must get them out of here .
Them ?
Tanith too .
Tanith is her real name .
This is her baptism as well .
Very well , we 'll do what we can .
( lively drum music ) ( followers shouting )
( speaking in foreign language )
( followers shouting )
( dramatic music )
My God .
( followers shouting )
The Goat of Mendes .
The Devil himself .
Let go .
You don 't understand , Rex .
It 's not just your life you 're risking , it 's your very soul .
Oh God , if only there was some light .
That 's it .
That 's it !
( dramatic music )
Wait , I 'll drive .
You get on the running board .
Kneel and face your master .
When we get to the bottom ,
throw that straight in the face of that damned monstrosity .
Right .
God help us then .
Who so dwelleth under the defense of the most high
shall abide under the shadow of the almighty .
( followers shouting )
( explosion booming )
Come on , Simon .
( doorbell ringing )
Hell of a way to turn up on their doorstep
after not having seen them since Christmas .
Good morning , Your Grace .
Good morning , Malin .
My niece and her husband , are they up yet ?
[ Malin ] Yes , sir , I imagine so .
Won 't you come in ?
Rex and Uncle Nicholas .
What 's the matter ?
You all look so ghastly .
I 'll explain all that ,
but first rooms for Ms. Carlisle and for Simon .
They 're both very badly in need of sleep .
Yes , of course .
No , I mustn 't , I mustn 't .
You do as I say , my dear .
Everything 's going to be all right .
Marie .
Yes , this way .
Simon .
I can wait , I want to hear what is said
and to make my apologies to you all .
Very well .
Rex , you stay with Tanith .
And if anything happens , you call me immediately .
You look as if you could do with some sleep yourself .
He could .
He 's been up all night .
I 'll take a nap later , but now we must talk .
[ Richard ] Bring us some coffee in , Malin .
[ Malin ] Yes , sir .
There .
I 'll go before it 's night again .
Well , you stay as long as you like .
No , no , I 'll go before it 's night .
Well , you try and get some sleep now .
Oh , Rex , what 's this all about ?
Well , your uncle will explain .
I wouldn 't know where to start .
Go to sleep .
I 'll be here .
Promise me .
Promise .
I don 't want to harm any of you .
No .
Why couldn 't we have met some other way ?
The way doesn 't matter .
It does , it does .
Does your friend possess any powers at all
to resist Mr. Mocata ?
We got you out of that bedlam last night , didn 't we ?
You 've got nothing to worry about , okay ?
I have everything to worry about .
[ Richard ] You 're quite serious about all this ?
Deadly serious .
It 's all true , Richard .
All of it .
God knows I wish it wasn 't .
None of us may eat today ?
Some fruit , a biscuit or two , some water .
[ Richard ] And no alcohol ?
I 'm sorry .
That is if we 're to stay .
Well , of course you 're staying .
But the danger .
[ Marie ] You think we 'd let you face it alone ?
You mean you believe all this ?
Well , I 'm damned .
You will find a talk with Rex most valuable , Richard .
His skepticism was fully the equal of yours .
Now he believes ?
Ask him .
Uncle Nicholas , how can we help ?
You 're already helping , my dear .
Simon 's resistance is practically nil because he 's been
under the influence of Mocata for so long .
The same thing applies to Ms. Carlisle .
Rex and I are at a very low ebb after last night .
Your coming fresh into the battle now
is of paramount importance .
Now I 've got to leave you all for a short while ,
but I 'll be back before nightfall .
Richard , I want you to sit with Simon while he sleeps .
You are not to allow him to get up under any circumstances .
Once he gets his head down , I imagine - -
[ Nicholas ] Under any circumstances .
All right .
He is not to be left alone for an instant , you understand ?
Not for an instant .
( dramatic music )
( doorbell ringing )
[ Mocata ] Good morning .
I would like to see Mrs. Eaton , please .
My card .
Will you please wait here , sir ?
There 's a gentleman to see you , madam , a Mr. Mocata .
Well , you better call Mister ...
No , wait a minute , I 'll see him in the library .
And Malin , if I ring , come at once .
You understand , immediately .
Yes , madam .
Will you come this way , sir ?
Thank you .
Please forgive me , Mrs. Eaton ,
for calling without an introduction .
But I 'm here on an errand of goodwill .
Goodwill ?
I 'm returning the property of a friend of yours ,
the Duc de Richleau .
His motorcar .
Oh , thank you .
[ Mocata ] May I introduce myself ?
Mocata , perhaps you 've heard my name ?
I 've certainly heard a great deal about you .
Ah , I thought that might be the case .
But whether the facts have been correctly represented to you
is something else again .
May I ?
Very well , but please be brief .
Of course .
I shan 't intrude on you a moment longer than is necessary .
Well , now as you probably know ,
Ms. Tanith and Simon are very close friends of mine .
Indeed ?
Yes , I believe they 're here now , is that correct ?
Why , how did you know that , Mr. Mocata ?
They only arrived a short while ago .
That is neither here nor there , you see .
The point is that there are certain matters ,
of which you are quite naturally unaware ,
which make it imperative that I should take them
back to London immediately .
Well , I 'm afraid that 's quite impossible .
I feared you would take that attitude .
I know the Duc de Richleau has been filling your mind
with all sorts of preposterous nonsense about me .
I know that what he said is true .
You realize that Tanith and Simon may be
in considerable danger if they do not leave this house .
On the contrary , they will be safe nowhere else .
Mrs. Eaton , it 's obvious that you distrust me .
And after what your friends have told you about me ,
I 'm not surprised in the least .
However , your obvious intelligence emboldens me
to think that I will serve my purpose best
by putting my cards on the table , as it were .
There is no more to be said .
- Please , hear me out . - ( eerie music )
Dear lady ,
I do not propose to discuss with you
the rights and wrongs of practicing the magic art .
I will confine myself to saying that
I am a practitioner of some experience .
Monsieur de Richleau has , no doubt , led you to believe
that I am thoroughly evil .
Such is not the case .
In magic , there is neither good nor evil .
It is merely a science , the science of causing change
to occur by means of one 's will .
The sinister reputation attaching to it
is entirely groundless and is based on superstition
rather than objective observation .
The power of the will is something people do not understand ,
attributing to it mysterious qualities
which it does not possess , being merely the power
of mind over matter or in the greater number of cases ,
the power of mind over mind .
As your mind now is succumbing to mine .
For as you look into my eyes and listen to my voice ,
your will is leaving you , slipping away ,
and you are now beneath my influence .
Although your eyes are open and you seem aware ,
you are , in fact , asleep , your faculties dormant ,
your ability to act and think subservient to my will .
My will .
Mrs. Eaton , my will is yours at this point .
You cannot function in the least , unless I say so , can you ?
Answer me , Mrs. Eaton .
No .
Where is Simon ?
Upstairs .
[ Mocata ] Alone ?
My husband is watching him .
And Tanith ?
[ Marie ] Upstairs .
Alone ?
No , Rex is with her .
( dramatic music )
Mummy , would you come and ...
Get out of this house , do you hear me ?
I want the girl and Simon .
Show him out .
I am leaving .
I shall not be back but something will .
Tonight , something will come for Simon and the girl .
Richard , what 's happened ?
Oh , nothing , apart from an attempt to strangle me .
What ?
He just woke up , tried to choke me ,
then went back to sleep again as if nothing had happened .
Mocata , he was here .
Why didn 't you tell me ?
Well , Uncle Nicholas said that Simon
must not be left alone for an instant .
Better see if Rex is all right .
Rex , Rex , wake up .
She 's gone .
What are you trying to do ?
What 's the matter , Tanith ?
Come on , we 'll go back .
No , I 'm not going back there .
Why not ?
I almost killed you .
Mocata was there .
Mocata ?
He came for me and Simon , but he didn 't succeed .
He won 't give up , can 't you see ?
I can 't go back there or he 'll make me do something terrible
to you and your friends .
I don 't want to hurt you .
I don 't want to hurt any of you .
All right , all right , we won 't go back .
We 'll find somewhere safe to stay until morning .
I saw you coming .
You look terribly tired .
Uncle Nicholas , Mocata 's been here .
What ?
He returned your car .
He didn 't harm you ?
No , no , no .
Simon , where 's Simon ?
Asleep .
You 're sure ?
Yes , Richard 's watching him .
And what about the girl ?
She 's gone .
Gone ?
Rex is with her .
He telephoned , but he wouldn 't say where .
What a fool he is .
Doesn 't he realize yet what we 're up against ?
She ran away when Mocata was here , and Rex went after her .
Then why on Earth didn 't he bring her back here then ?
He explained on the phone .
It 's through Tanith that Mocata makes his attacks .
She 's his medium .
That 's why she 's gone .
She doesn 't want to be close to us .
Then why is Rex with her ?
To try and prevent Mocata from gaining control over her .
Pray God he can .
As long as it 's light , it may be possible .
But once the darkness begins to fall - -
( dramatic music ) ( Tanith screaming )
It 's nearly dark .
Where 's Simon ?
Saying good night to Peggy in the nursery .
What do you want to do about supper ?
Water , Richard , just water .
All right .
[ Marie ] God bless you , my angel .
Good night , Mummy .
Good night .
I 've cleared all the furniture out
of the drawing room , Your Grace , as you requested .
Thank you , Malin .
You 're to stay with Ms. Peggy
until I tell you otherwise , do you understand ?
Now to work .
( Tanith screaming )
All right now .
He must be getting weaker .
He 's been attacking you all afternoon .
No , he won 't stop .
It 's too important for him .
But why doesn 't he come at me with a gun or something ?
He never risks himself in any way .
I can believe that , but this isn 't doing him any good .
What now ?
Now we wait .
( dramatic music )
No .
( wind whistling )
Frankly , I think we 're behaving like a pack of idiots .
It begins .
What , what begins ?
Mocata is working on you because you are the weakest link .
From his point of view , Richard .
You are the skeptical one .
He is looking for an easy way to break the circle .
Come on , will you ?
Is there anything I could say right now
that you wouldn 't interpret in your own suspicious way ?
Richard .
Well , it 's all superstition , black magic .
Hell , I 'm going for a drink .
Richard .
You and I have been friends for many years , haven 't we ?
I don 't follow you .
If I begged you , for the sake of that friendship ,
to do something for me , would you do it ?
You know I would .
Very well .
Then will you stay with me in the circle tonight ?
You are unafraid .
I am not .
That 's a pretty low trick , appealing to friendship .
Will you stay ?
What else can I do ?
I wish we had some water .
We have .
What ?
There .
Yes .
Where do you get your water from , a swamp ?
What ?
- Taste it . - No , don 't touch it .
All right , I 'll get some fresh .
No , that 's exactly what he wants you to do .
What is it ?
I 'm not certain , but ...
[ Marie ] What ?
The lights .
[ Richard ] What about the lights ?
They seem to be dimmer .
[ Richard ] No , they 're not .
Yes .
I don 't know what you 're ...
It 's getting colder .
This is to be expected .
It 's only the beginning .
On your feet , quickly !
Back to back , join hands .
( wind whistling )
Easy , darling , it 's all over now .
( knocking )
[ Rex ] Hey , what 's going on in there ?
Let me in .
Stay still .
No !
[ Rex ] Oh , come on , let me in .
It 's cold out here , let me in .
We must let him in .
Who ?
Do you think that 's Rex out there ?
[ Rex ] Let me in .
Let me in .
What 's that ?
( Marie screams )
( Marie screams ) Don 't leave the circle !
[ Richard ] There 's a light in the hall .
Peggy !
- No , Peggy ! - No , Marie , no !
Let me go !
Run !
- It 's not Peggy . - Peggy !
You 're out of your mind .
Simon !
( Marie screams )
I tell you , it 's not Peggy !
[ Marie ] Peggy ! ( sobs )
Let go of me !
She 's upstairs , asleep .
Oh God , Peggy .
( Marie screams )
I won 't , don 't you hear me ?
I won 't !
Simon , no !
No , Simon , no .
( Marie sobs )
Back to back , quickly .
Can 't we do anything but just stand here ?
Isn 't there any way of fighting back ?
Only one .
What ?
The last two lines of the Sussamma Ritual .
For God 's sake , then what are you waiting for ?
I daren 't use them until our very souls
are in peril of destruction .
To do so would destroy us as effectively
as it would stop Mocata .
It could alter time and space and - -
( hooves clopping )
What is it ?
He has given up trying to get Simon .
He has sent the Angel of Death himself to claim him .
And us ?
If he once breaks into the circle .
If we once catch sight of his face .
( horse whinnying )
For God 's sake , Nicholas , say it !
I can 't .
( horse whinnying )
( Marie screams )
Richleau !
( speaking in foreign language )
( dramatic music )
It 's over ?
Yes , Simon , it 's all over .
She 's dead .
I know , Rex .
The Angel of Death was summoned .
He cannot return empty-handed .
I 'll go and see how Peggy is .
Miss Peggy , she is gone .
What ?
What happened ?
I was watching her when suddenly a kind of darkness
came over me .
I couldn 't see , I couldn 't hear .
There was nothing I could do , I swear it .
I know , Malin , I know .
No .
Oh my God .
He 's got her , hasn 't he ?
( engine revving )
Simon !
Don 't try to follow him , Richard .
Mocata will know he 's coming .
To follow him would be suicide .
What are we to do then ?
How are we going to find Mocata ?
Before me , Raphael .
Behind me , Gabriel .
On my right hand , Michael .
On my left hand , Auriel .
In the name of these mighty spirits ,
I conjure you , Tanith , wherever you may be .
Join us in this circle that you may speak with us .
With salt , I summon thee .
With hair , I summon thee .
With blood , I summon thee .
( liquid hisses )
The sign of Osiris slain .
The sign of Osiris risen .
You have called me , I am here .
Are you in truth Tanith ?
I am .
[ Nicholas ] Do you acknowledge our Lord , Jesus Christ ?
[ Tanith ] I do .
Did you come here of your own free will ?
I came because you summoned me .
I came willingly .
There is one here whose grief at your passing
is very great .
He has agreed that you will be summoned back
only in the hope that you will help him
to protect his friends from evil .
Will you help him ?
I will because I love him .
Then tell us where Mocata is .
I do not know .
Try to find him .
I cannot see him clearly .
He covers himself with a cloak of darkness .
I see the child though , a little girl .
[ Nicholas ] Where ?
I cannot enter .
You must .
I cannot .
The winged serpent guards the way .
I cannot enter .
Where ?
I cannot see .
You must see .
You must enter .
I command you to enter .
No , please .
He is in there , the dark one .
Please , don 't make me enter .
You must enter .
No , no , please .
I command you to enter .
No !
Yes , now !
I cannot !
Stop it !
( Tanith screams )
You fool , you damned fool !
She 's all right .
You might have killed her .
A winged serpent guarding the way .
But where ?
On the gates of that house .
Welcome back , my son .
All right , I 'm back .
You can release the child now .
Yes , I have you back .
Now I don 't have to release the child , do I ?
What do you mean ?
You have no use for her .
Ah , but I do , my son .
A most important use .
I have you back .
Now the only one I need is Tanith .
- You wouldn 't - - - Dare ?
( dramatic music )
Take your place .
Now that our coven of 13 has been restored ,
we can begin the ceremony .
Bring in the child .
Now whatever you see , whatever happens , stay close to me .
God knows what we will find in there .
Almighty and all powerful Set , father of darkness ,
king of death , I pledge this knife to you .
( Marie screams )
Rex !
No , Richard , no !
Mocata !
( blows thudding )
Welcome to our circle .
What have you done to my baby ?
She does not hear you .
She 's in a state of deep hypnosis .
In the name of God , you dare not !
Scarcely in the name of God , Monsieur le Duc .
What 's he going to do with her ?
Uncle ?
Take me instead , Mocata .
You , Monsieur le Duc ?
Your soul in preference to that of an unstained child ?
What 's he talking about ?
He isn 't going to - -
Yes , the transference of souls .
That of your child for that of Tanith .
No !
( dramatic music )
( blows thudding )
Now if our two remaining guests will permit ,
we may proceed .
Almighty and all powerful Set ,
father of darkness , king of death ,
I pledge this knife to thee , to do thy work
and be thy servant .
Those words you said before , say them again .
[ Mocata ] And the blood of this child shall be - -
I cannot .
You must .
[ Mocata ] The end is known not even to us .
My baby 's going to die if you don 't .
You must speak those words again .
The bride of chaos .
[ Followers ] The bride of chaos .
The rider upon the beast .
[ Followers ] The rider upon the beast .
With this knife do I draw out the blood
which is thy life .
[ Tanith ] Only they who love without desire
shall have power granted them in their darkest hour .
( followers gasping )
Peggy , get up .
Repeat after me the words of the Sussamma Ritual .
( speaking in foreign language )
( lightning crashes ) ( followers scream )
( flames roaring )
( followers scream )
( heavenly music )
It 's over ?
Yes , Simon , it 's all over .
Peggy .
Wasn 't ...
Tanith .
Come in , my friends .
She 's all right .
Tanith !
Time itself has been reversed for us .
Tanith 's death , Peggy 's abduction ,
the ride to Chilbury , the ritual in the cellar ,
all these things happened , but now they have not happened .
We are back .
We are all safe again .
And is Mocata also safe ?
You will also remember , Simon , what I said to you
about the Angel of Death .
Once being summoned - -
Cannot return empty-handed .
Exactly .
Tanith has been restored to us , but the age-old law
demands a life for a life , a soul for a soul .
And there is only one man in all this world
who can replace her life , her soul .
The man who invoked the Angel of Death .
Mocata is dead .
Thank God .
Yes , Simon .
He is the one we must thank .
( dramatic music )